<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Wondrous Items</name>
		<update version="0.0.2">
			<file name="items-wondrous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/core/dungeon-masters-guide/items/items-wondrous.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Figurine of Wondrous Power, Katarische Sea Horse" type="Magic Item" source="World of Royan: Chaos Rift" id="ID_JBTF_WOR_CR_ITEM_FIGURINE_OF_WONDROUS_POWER_CORAL_SEA_HORSE">
		<description>
			<p>A <em>figurine of wondrous power</em> is a statuette of a beast small enough to fit in a pocket. If you use an action to speak the command word and throw the figurine to a point on the ground within 60 feet of you, the figurine becomes a living creature. If the space where the creature would appear is occupied by other creatures or objects, or if there isn't enough space for the creature, the figurine doesn't become a creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">The creature is friendly to you and your companions. It understands your languages and obeys your spoken commands. If you issue no commands, the creature defends itself but takes no other actions.</p>
			<p class="indent">The creature exists for a duration specific to each figurine. At the end of the duration, the creature reverts to its figurine form. It reverts to a figurine early if it drops to 0 hit points or if you use an action to speak the command word again while touching it. When the creature becomes a figurine again, its property can't be used again until a certain amount of time has passed, as specified in the figurine's description.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Katarische Sea Horse(Uncommon).</em></strong> This statuette of a sea horse is made of a light pink coral material and is small enough to fit in your pocket. Using an action to speak its command word transforms the figurine into a living giant sea horse, that obeys your commands. It can become a giant sea horse for up to 6 hours and can be ridden as a mount while in water. Once it has been used, it can't be used againt until 2 days have passed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Gauntlets of Grimlock Power" type="Magic Item" source="World of Royan: Chaos Rift" id="ID_JBTF_WOR_CR_MAGIC_ITEM_GAUNTLETS_OF_GRIMLOCK_POWER">
		<description>
			<p>Your Strength score is 16 while you wear these gauntlets. They have no effect on you if your Strength is 16 or higher without them.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">strength</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength:score:set" value="16" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Tricorn Hat of Influence" type="Magic Item" source="World of Royan: Chaos Rift" id="ID_JBTF_WOR_CR_MAGIC_ITEM_TRICORN_OF_INFLUENCE">
		<description>
			<p>This hat has 5 charges. As a bonus action, you may touch the brim of the hat to expend a charge and activate its effect. While activated, the hat gives you advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) checks and Charisma (Intimidation) checks.</p>
			<p class="indent">The effect last for 10 minutes. The hat regains 1d4 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Utility Belt of the Night Gnome" type="Magic Item" source="World of Royan: Chaos Rift" id="ID_JBTF_WOR_CR_MAGIC_ITEM_UTILITY_BELT_OF_THE_NIGHT_GNOME">
		<description>
			<p>The legend of the Night Gnome lives on. A thousand years children and evildoers have been afraid of the dark. The Night Gnome might just get you! The utility belt helps to channel and control magic. This apparatus is a collection of leather straps, flexible tubing, glass cylinders, and fittings made from a magic-infused metal alloy, all assembled into a small belt one can wear as a belt. Handy!. The item weighs 5 pounds.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you are wearing the utility belt, you can use it as an arcane focus. In addition, you can attempt to cast a spell that you do not know or have prepared. The spell you choose must be on your class's spell list and of a level for which you have a spell slot, and you must provide the spell's components.</p>
			<p class="indent">You expend a spell slot to cast the spell as normal, but before resolving it you must make an Intelligence (Arcana) check. The DC is 10 + twice the level of the spell slot you expend to cast the spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">On a successful check, you cast the spell as normal, using your spell save DC and spellcasting ability modifier. On a failed check, you cast a different spell from the one you intended. Randomly determine the spell you cast by rolling on the table for the level of the spell slot you expended. If the slot is 6th level or higher, roll on the table for 5th-level spells.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you try to cast a cantrip you don't know, the DC for the Intelligence (Arcana) check is 10, and on a failed check, there is no effect. The belt can only be used by by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard</p>
			<h5>1ST-LEVEL SPELLS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d6</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>burning hands</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>chaos bolt</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>color spray</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>faerie fire</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>fog cloud</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>thunderwave</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h5>2ND-LEVEL SPELLS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d6</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>blur</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>gust of wind</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>heat metal</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Melf's acid arrow</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>scorching ray</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>shatter</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h5>3RD-LEVEL SPELLS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d6</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>fear</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>feign death</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>fireball</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>gaseous form</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>sleet storm</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>stinking cloud</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h5>4TH-LEVEL SPELLS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d4</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>confusion</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>conjure minor elementals</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Evard's black tentacles</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>ice storm</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h5>5TH-LEVEL SPELLS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d4</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>animate objects</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>cloudkill</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>cone of cold</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>flame strike</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="8">8 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	
	
</elements>